Finding Aid for the Robert T. Lagemann Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Robert T. Lagemann Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0245
60 linear feet
- Note cards (Box 1)
- Note cards (Box 2)
- Note cards (Box 3)
- Note cards (Box 4)
- Scientific catalogs (Box 5)
- Biographical material on various science figures (Box 6)
- Biographical material on various science figures (Box 7)
- Research on Barnard for history of physics at VU book (Box 8)
- Correspondence with William Sheehan, who was preparing book on EEB for Cambridge University Press (Box 8)
- Lectures and lecture notes (Box 9)
- Research notes (Box 9)
- Advice to grad students on submitting papers to professional journals (Box 9)
- Paper submitted to Office of War Information c1945 on “Possibilities for Industrial Use of Atomic Energy” – approved for release by authorities of Manhattan project – translated & broadcast to Italy, c1947 (Box 9)
- Research on Barnard for history of physics at VU book (Box 10)
- Correspondence with William Sheehan, who was preparing book on EEB for Cambridge University Press (Box 10)
- Research on Barnard for history of physics at VU book (Box 11)
- Correspondence with William Sheehan, who was preparing book on EEB for Cambridge University Press (Box 11)
- Research on Barnard for history of physics at VU book (Box 12)
- Correspondence with William Sheehan, who was preparing book on EEB for Cambridge University Press (Box 12)
- Biographical material on various science figures (Box 13)
- Biographical material on various science figures (Box 14)
- Biographical material on various science figures (Box 15)
- Physics program development, 1960s-1980s (Box 16)
- Administrative files (Box 16)
- Writings (Box 16)
- List of publications (Box 16)
- List of theses directed by Lagemann (Box 16)
- Book contracts, c1950s-1960s (Box 16)
- Personal papers (Box 16)
- Resignation from VU (Box 16)
- Salary letters (Box 16)
- Awards won (Box 16)
- Miscellaneous subject files (Box 17)
- Planning studies for physics department (Box 17)
- Talks given (Box 17)
- Subject files (Box 18)
- Administrative papers (Box 18)
- Writings (Box 18)
- Reel-to-reel of campus radio broadcast (Box 18)
- Alexander Winchell material, c1879/80 (Box 19)
- Biographical material on early science figures at VU and elsewhere (Box 19)
- Moon landing material, 1969 (Box 19)
- Teaching material and associated research (Box 19)
- Nuclear physics (Box 19)
- Wire models in optics (Box 19)
- Liquid air (Box 19)
- Surface tension, etc (Box 19)
- Subject files (Box 20)
- Teaching notes and material (Box 20)
- People subject files (Box 21)
- Photographs (Box 21)
- Photos on variety of science figures/people and topics Anti-gravity experiments photo (Box 22)
- Research notes for book on VU physics department (Box 22)
- Subject files (Box 23)
- Administrative papers (Box 23)
- History of graduate program (Box 23)
- VU book research (Box 24)
- Subject files (Box 24)
- Current (Box 25)
- Current (Box 26)
- Research Instruments (Box 27)
- Landon Cabell Garland material (Box 28)
- Landon Cabell Garland material (Box 29)
- Landon Cabell Garland material (Box 30)
- History of the Physics Department (Box 31)
- History of the Physics Department (Box 32)
- History of the Physics Department (Box 33)
- History of the Physics Department (Box 34)
- Books published (Box 35)
- Books published (Box 36)
- Correspondence (Box 37)
- Correspondence (Box 38)
- Landon Cabell Garland (Box 38)
- Correspondence (Box 39)
- Correspondence (Box 40)
- Correspondence (Box 41)
- Manhattan project (Box 42)
- WW II material (Box 42)
- Research notes, c1970s (Box 42)
- Lab notebooks, 1930s (Box 42)
- Calendars (Box 43)
- Miscellaneous (Box 43)
- Biographies of professors (Box 44)
- Biographies of professors (Box 45)
- Administrative papers (Box 45)
- Coursework material (Box 46)
- Coursework material (Box 47)